<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sreepriya Radhakrishnan</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 21:08:22 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 21:08:22 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>First ever Pehia Summit</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;A thank you note to the team behind the Pehia Summit 2020, who made the annual conference of Pehia Foundation a remarkable one.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-15.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A one day conference of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pehia Foundation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was our three-year goal.
I’m happy that we took a big step initiating this in the second year itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pehia Summit 2020&lt;/strong&gt; was a collective effort of team Pehia with around 15 volunteers from all over Kerala. Volunteers made it happen, I must say, even though they were spamming my inbox with silly doubts. It reminded me about us(Me and Enfa). How unorganized we were and how we organized our very first event. The mistakes we did. I remember the last-minute changes happening every time. No matter how much we plan, something will happen unexpectedly. This time also it happened and it was beyond our control. One of our speaker’s flight got cancelled and the other got delayed. We were not a pro in organizing events.
Organizing such an event in such a short time was exciting. I’ve already exceeded the number of leaves I could take during this year of fellowship. I was worried about my presence at the event. Thanks to Meera and Henna allowing me to join the Pehia Summit 2020(with a not taking leaving policy for next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-14.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting from volunteers selection, it was fun. We wanted to give the opportunity to newbies. I don’t know how to thank them. My little sisters! You’re next, take the lead and inspire others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shared the volunteer registration form only among our closest circles and was open for two days. It was fun scheduling hangouts call with all the twenty registered volunteers. One to one conversation. I appreciate them for their patience during the selection process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I haven’t seen any of our volunteers before. Soon we become a family. They made me realise that I’m no longer a small girl by calling me “chechi chechi” all the time, even though I have told them to call me by my name. 22! Oh my god, I’m ageing so fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-16.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think things were pretty clear to Me and Enfa this time that we divided the overall responsibility. When I look back, I realise things were more organized than they were. I do remember Enfa calling me and telling me that “ It seems like everything is done, but still have a gut feeling that there is something that we are missing. “&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything was just perfect.
The team, the energy. Everything!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I should thank each team individually for making this event a remarkable one. Our guests were so impressed with our guest relations team. From the way, they draft their email to their follow up with everything. We got really good feedback from our guests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was never good with creatives. Our deco team have done amazing work. I really love the wings, selfie stand and properties they have made. It did add colours to our event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-13.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our official driver, Diya Liza Varghese. You are a rock star, my love. You handled everything alone.
Venue team, Food team, Relationship and Partnership team, After Summit team everyone did their best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best things I notice in the food team was they did segregate the waste. Thank you guys for doing that. Anyone can acquire knowledge, but the real knowledge comes when you put it into practice. Proud of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much my bold and beautiful sisters. Pehia Summit 2020 was yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;future-of-pehia-summit&quot;&gt;Future of Pehia Summit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-18.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I envision Pehia summit as a conference were both the members of our programs and their parents can participate for free of cost. Pehia summit will be an opportunity for everyone to demonstrate their talent. A room for parents to raise their concerns and discuss how we can solve the challenges we face, with the complete support of our families. The moment we (Me and Enfa) had a conversation regarding Pehia annual conference, these are the things that came to my mind. I hope in the coming years Pehia Foundation can do so much in revolutionizing the technology industry as well as the society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-17.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/26/pehia-summit-2020/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/01/26/pehia-summit-2020/</guid>
        
        <category>--</category>
        
        <category>Pehia</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pehia Foundation Pre Summit 2020</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;An informal meetup organized a day before Pehia Summit 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My sincere thanks to my partner in crime Anusree S for organizing Pehia Pre-summit Meet up.
Initially, I was thinking about organizing a day workshop on 25th Jan 2020. In such a short time frame it was difficult to finalize a topic and find speakers for the workshop. Anusree put forth the idea of having an informal meetup before the summit. I had the wow feeling inside me when she explained how she wants the meetup to be. We kept it open for everyone(all women), working in all fields. We were encouraging our members to bring their mothers to the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anusree has put her cent percentage for organizing such a fruitful informal meetup, I must say. The creative memes she has come up with was so amazing. There are a few more memes that we didn’t publish due to lack of time. Here I would like to share those and wish I could get some honest feedback on her creatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-did-we-want-to-do-an-informal-meetup&quot;&gt;Why did we want to do an informal meetup?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-6.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Community&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is all about providing an inclusive environment, right? If an individual starts feeling that this community is not for them., then what happens? If the community is not addressing its member’s issues properly, what is the purpose of the community then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-7.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These questions led us to have an informal meet up to connect with our members. It was more like listening to them about their expectations from Pehia as a community. We started Pehia Foundation to encourage women to code more, attend events more and boost their confidence so that they become self-aware about their ability and capacity to achieve their dreams.
Pehia’s Pre-summit meetup, it was not a supersized meetup but a set of diverse people can in and around Kochi came to talk about their dreams. It was a three-hour meetup. I do remember the face of a few attendees. They were nervous, not talking at all. They were confused about the event, that what’s going to happen here? Is this a class? What we are going to talk about etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-8.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I had in mind for them was to give a community where they feel that it’s theirs. I wanted them to ask me at the end of the meetup that is there any tickets left to register for the Pehia Summit. I wanted them to feel the fire inside each team member of Pehia and get inspired by them to do more, to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-10.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spend the last thirty minutes discussing the struggles they are facing to pursue their dreams, be it at home, college, or in the society. Faheena, an MSc rank holder who is struggling to come back to her career. I’m sure she has inspired everyone in the room. She acknowledged the level of confort she felt with the Pehia team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-11.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was all we wanted. Provide our members with a comfortable space where then can share their stories and listen to other’s stories as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/25/pre-summit2020/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/01/25/pre-summit2020/</guid>
        
        <category>--</category>
        
        <category>Pehia</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interested in Mentoring Children? Seize this opportunity!!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m Sreepriya Radhakrishnan, currently working as a STEM Fellow with &lt;a href=&quot;https://universesimplified.org&quot;&gt;Universe Simplified Foundation&lt;/a&gt;. They started this two-year fellowship program last year and I was lucky enough to get selected for this fellowship. The application for the next cohort is open right now. You can apply here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also shared the details on all my social media handles. So many people texted me their queries about this fellowship. Being the USF STEM fellow, I thought it would be nice if I write about this fellowship and my fellowship experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-little-bit-about-universe-simplified-foundation&quot;&gt;A little bit about Universe Simplified Foundation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-20.png&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Universe Simplified is a section 8 company based in Mumbai focused on STEM(Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics) education of kids. They were active for the last six years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;if-you-want-to-know-about-usf-more-read-the-blog-posts&quot;&gt;If you want to know about USF more, read the blog posts.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;About USF&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Innovation Module&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the USF website, they have mentioned the roles and responsibilities of a fellow in this fellowship period. That’s very short. I can tell you, you will learn more about STEM education, children learning the mindset and about yourself a lot during this fellowship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;usf-is-different&quot;&gt;USF is DIFFERENT!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approach of USF is very different from other educational organizations I’ve seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inquiry-driven, collaborative learning and doing hands-on projects. One of the main things I liked about USF is apart from the curriculum USF has, they ask children about what they want to learn. Rather than teaching children a particular topic, USF provide mentor-ship to children. Guiding them in the right direction by asking the right questions to children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I took feedback from one of the class teacher of children we’re working with, she said that children started asking questions during physics class without any hesitation or rather than just listening to the theory and taking notes, children started to ask questions about the practical application of certain principles. That was a heart-touching moment for me. I felt like we went one step closer to the vision of our organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-19.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-should-you-apply-for-this-fellowship&quot;&gt;Why should you apply for this fellowship?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re willing to spend two years building your interpersonal skills and knowledge in the STEM sector, you should definitely apply for this fellowship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;if-youre&quot;&gt;If you’re&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interested in teaching kids&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Looking for an opportunity to explore STEM&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thinking about personal development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keen on managing people&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Someone love to make projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be one of the best opportunities for you. What are you waiting for? Seize this opportunity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;apply-now&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://universesimplified.org/usf-stem-fellowship/&quot;&gt;APPLY NOW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/04/usf-fellowship-application/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/12/04/usf-fellowship-application/</guid>
        
        <category>--</category>
        
        <category>Work</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Having fun with Arduino</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;neverstoplearningnewthings&quot;&gt;#NeverStopLearningNewThings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-27.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I’m from Computer Science background and electronics were one of the core subject I choose during my graduation, to be honest I’ve never touched a resistor in my life. Thanks to our education system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Meera (Cofounder &amp;amp; Program Manager of USF) said that I’ve to start learning Arduino, I had a panic attack. I don’t know anything about Arduino- where to start and how to do. The one and only person’s name that came to my mind was Salman Faris. I immediately texted him and bombarded him with all my insecurities about learning Arduino. He suggested a few resources where I can start learning Arduino. He introduced to Kerala Hackster.io community — an online community for hardware hackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few resources were you can start learning Arduino,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arduino.cc&quot;&gt;Arduino Official Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.makerspaces.com&quot;&gt;Maker Space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instructables.com/circuits/arduino/projects/&quot;&gt;Instructables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“You never know until you try”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-28.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with Arduino is magic, it’s fun and the excitement is another level. Meera, she bought me a lot of sensors. A lot means A LOT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Learning by teaching”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best learning method ever. I’m mentoring children to program Arduino at one of the Innovation Hubs of USF. Learning with children is fun. The way they solve challenges is way different from our imagination. They surprise me most of the time with their findings and confusions. Most of the time I feel like I’ve to learn a lot from them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/11/28/arduino-01/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/11/28/arduino-01/</guid>
        
        <category>--</category>
        
        <category>Work</category>
        
        <category>Learn</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Six months with USF</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Time is flying. I can’t believe how fast the last six months went by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyday with USF, I’m becoming a better version of myself. The self-realization I had in the last few months is incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to be clear about ourselves, right? Or I believe that it’s really important to know what I am and where I need to improve to fit in the world I choose to be with.
USF Program&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, USF is running a 32 session program with schools and community centres in Maharashtra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program is divided into two parts, before Diwali and after Diwali. Around sixteen sessions happened before Diwali in our Innovation Hubs in the last four months. In the past sixteen sessions, children were solving challenges given to them using materials available in each hub. In the next sixteen sessions, children will apply the knowledge they have acquired during the previous sessions. We called it the “Innovation Module”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-innovation-module&quot;&gt;What is Innovation Module?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its a sixteen session program where children will come up with real-life challenges they are facing and solve it. Once they choose a challenge they want to solve, they research, ideate and prototype their solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so excited about the challenges they have identified and the solution they are going to come up with. The next few months will be the months where creativity, problem solving and learnings take place. And the new batch of interns are so amazing soon we become a family. Training days are the best days with interns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much curiosity and excitement for Innovation Module.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/11/11/usf-six-months/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/11/11/usf-six-months/</guid>
        
        <category>--</category>
        
        <category>Work</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pehia’s CODERENE</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-24.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt really happy that my recent home visit and &lt;strong&gt;Pehia’s CODERENE&lt;/strong&gt; happened at the same time. It wasn’t a preplanned visit. Anyway, I was happy to be there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations and good work to &lt;strong&gt;Arya Lakshmi&lt;/strong&gt;, the key person behind the CODERENE- Pehia’s online coding competition. She fantastically handles the online coding competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-25.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;
Around seventeen girls who love programming and one boy who loves programming made this event a successful one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is always a misconception about Pehia’s events. Many people assume Pehia’s event as women only event. It’s true that we host events exclusively for women. But not all events. It’s NOT ONLY FOR GIRLS. It’s for everyone. Almost every event of Pehia, 25% we expect participation from other genders. We create an inclusive environment because we believe that diversity can only be achieved by being inclusive. So next time if you’re confused about participation in any event of Pehia drop your queries at&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;h e l l o [at] p e h i a . o r g&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;s r e e [at] p e h i a . o r g&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/30/pehia-coderene/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/10/30/pehia-coderene/</guid>
        
        <category>--</category>
        
        <category>Pehia</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Story of a successful crowdfunding campaign</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;A goal without a plan is just a wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got an opportunity to attend &lt;a href=&quot;https://cmxhub.com/summit2019/&quot;&gt;CMX Summit 2019&lt;/a&gt; which happened at Redwood City, California with a scholarship. As a scholarship amount I got $700 but I needed around $1500 more for my visa, travel &amp;amp; stay. Through crowdfunding I raised the rest of the amount. Thanks to everyone who supported and contributed to my campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a friendly blog that comprises the plan and action of my crowdfunding campaign. I hope it helps someone to run their campaign successfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me around a week to properly plan my campaign. I had no clue about how this will work. Thanks to &lt;em&gt;Arya Murali&lt;/em&gt; for her blog &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@aryamurali/0-tips-to-run-a-successful-crowd-funding-campaign-eb82901f52cb&quot;&gt;10 tips to run a successful crowdfunding campaign&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some information about how I run my CF campaign:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-select-a-crowdfunding-platform&quot;&gt;1. Select a Crowdfunding Platform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of CF platforms on the internet. Thoroughly read the terms &amp;amp; conditions. For my CF campaign, I choose Ketto.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-i-choose-kettoorg&quot;&gt;Why I choose Ketto.org?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the most familiar crowdfunding platform in my circle. That’s the main reason I choose Ketto. There are a few things you need to keep in mind when you start a campaign in Ketto for personal needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For personal needs, Ketto charges 5% of the total amount raised as Ketto Fee.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can do your first withdrawal, only after hitting 50% of your goal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can withdraw contributions in $ during the campaign only if you’ve got a contribution in $ above or equal to $500.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The fund will get transferred to your account within 3–5 business days from the date of your withdraw request.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even if you didn’t reach your goal, you are able to withdraw whatever amount you’ve raised within 15 days after the campaign end date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ketto have an amazing dashboard where you can see not just the successful transaction but also the failed transactions too. You can see the number of profile visits each day, the number of contributions in a day and, the amount raised in a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-29.png&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-budget&quot;&gt;2. Budget&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing you should do when you’re planning a trip. Most of the crowdfunding platforms have fees. Like I said before Ketto charges 5% of the total amount as the fee, therefore, decide the amount you’ve to raise through crowdfunding accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I crowdfunded not only for my air tickets to San Fransisco but also for my visa, stay and travel in the US for twelve days. The estimated amount including air ticket, B1/B2 US visa application, stay, travel was around $2100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I had a scholarship amount of $700 from CMX hub, around $1400 I had to raise through CF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-friends-and-family--your-personal-publicity-volunteer&quot;&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Friends and Family = Your Personal Publicity Volunteer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust me these people can make your campaign go viral. They are your biggest supporters and marketers. Some of them could become your potential contributors too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$1&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;$100&lt;/strong&gt; tell your close ones to contribute. Keep money flow every day during your campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before starting your campaign, get your friends and family ready for the blast. Inform them, call everyone if possible, let them know what you’re going to do and take them with you on the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It worked for me. I got immense support from my friends and family, from sharing campaign links to the campaign updates they were with me. Put everyone on the pressure to share and support your campaign. With strong ties and weak ties, your campaign can become a movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-about-the-campaign&quot;&gt;4. About the campaign&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell them a compelling story. &lt;strong&gt;“Story Telling”&lt;/strong&gt; is the best method to grab the attention of your audience. I wanted my story very simple and friendly. There is some key points you should cover in your story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I call it &lt;strong&gt;3 Ws&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;W&lt;/strong&gt;hat is the purpose of your campaign?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;W&lt;/strong&gt;hy this amount?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;W&lt;/strong&gt;hy should they contribute?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content you provide to your contributor’s matters a lot. It should be like when you read your final draft you should feel to contribute to this campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PS: Always think as a contributor when you write your story.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-30.png&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-social-media-post&quot;&gt;5. Social Media Post&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should give campaign updates to your supports and contributors and at the same time, you don’t have to spam their feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A timely update is very important. The nature of updates should be different in different mediums. I choose Facebook, WhatsApp &amp;amp; Instagram for my daily updates. Use Twitter and Ketto.org page for important updates like when I reach 50%, 80% and 102% of my goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be creative&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make others feel that this opportunity is very important and special for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be nice if you can create a template for posters so that you can use it throughout your campaign. Since I’m miserable at designing, my posters were not that cool (Sadly agree). But I tried to be a little creative. The cover picture of my campaign was a picture of Aeroplane (which I drew using a pencil) and my passport and a pencil. I really loved my work (Self-appraisal, LOL).
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-31.png&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-connect-your-contributors&quot;&gt;6. Connect your contributors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email is the best way to connect to your contributors. Remember don’t spam their inbox. I mailed them for the first time when I achieve my target. I used the same cover picture for thanking them with a small change, I gave colors to my Aeroplane as they(my contributors) gave colors to my dreams. There were only 66 contributors. I tried to not to automate emails. I mailed everyone personally. I couldn’t thank them enough for the love and support they gave me. Each and every reply from them filled my heart with love and my eyes with tears. When you write to them make it personalized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-32.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-33.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of mistakes I did in planning. I started my campaign at month-end and best practice it to start it at the beginning of the month because that’s the time everyone has salary in their account. I failed to post an update on Ketto pages. Running a crowdfunding campaign is like multitasking. You need to handle multiple roles. You have to be a content writer, social media marketer, public relations specialist, and project manager. Those 16 days were special. From receiving the first contribution in the midnight to ending the campaign with 102% of my goal was really exciting. Once again thanks to all my friends, family for your support and contribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-34.png&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/08/15/crowdfunding-campaign/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/08/15/crowdfunding-campaign/</guid>
        
        <category>--</category>
        
        <category>Projects</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jab we met</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I met &lt;strong&gt;Enfa Rose George&lt;/strong&gt; for the first time at Rajagiri School of Engineering, Kakkanad. She was a first-year IT student at that time. I went there to attend a ReactJS workshop organized by FOSS Club Kerala. It was the first workshop I ever attended and to my knowledge, it was the first workshop Enfa organized at her college. The workshop went very well and I met a lot of new people who are a good friend of mine now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to FOSS Club STAS(School of Technology and Applied Sciences), where I got the updates regarding the technical workshops nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the ReactJS workshop and networking session, when Enfa sends me off with a sweet “Good Bye!” I never thought of meeting her again. But destiny has planned something else for us. I met her again on another technology meet-ups. And we used to see each other every weekend at some events or workshops or meet-ups and become friends. I haven’t seen any girls rather than us in events or workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the time the &lt;a href=&quot;https://studevsoc.com&quot;&gt;Student Developer Society&lt;/a&gt; has formed. Levi, my senior’s initiative. SDS is celebrating its second birthday today. Congratulations Levi and thank you so much for introducing me to the community world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-59.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took my initial community lessons for SDS. From how to keep your community members active to organize events.
With the help of a few like-minded people, we decided to host the inaugural ceremony at our college STAS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my surprise, Venkat sir, ( mentor of Sds) selected me to be in the core group of SDS, Enfa as well selected as the core member of SDS.Me, Enfa, Prejith, Jesvin Levi, Venkat, and Ajin Jude. We were the team! We organized monthly meetups and workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-60.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, SDS was WhatsApp group (currently the main group is in telegram Join: @studevsoc). Students and professionals from different places joined the group. People started posting events happening in and around Kerala, and discussions on different topics occurred.
SDS is very special to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;
Two years ago, we embarked on a journey with a unique mission. To bridge the gap between students and professionals and to empower the students with a taste of the professional world.Today, our journey still continues. We have sailed across various obstacles, various chapters, dark phases and challenges. Yet, we sail strong. We have achieved and done a lot, but we know we have a lot more to explore. We have many more chapters to come, many more phases to pass, many more obstacles to jump over and many more challeges to come. Our journey towards our goal continues…Happy 2nd Birthday Student Developers Society. — Levi, Founder SDS
&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-61.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our friendship grew with SDS. Core meetings, organizing meetups, attending events, we were everywhere together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we both got selected for a three-day hackathon organized by ICFOSS, TVM. I was pretty sure when I got the selection mail, that my parents are not going to allow me to go for this event. Enfa faced the same issue. We decided to go together. Still, that wasn’t enough for our families. After so much effort of talking to our parents, they together come to a decision that my parents will take us to Trivandrum and they will come to take us back too. The journey we started from there is still going on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholer-62.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/07/29/the-unexpected-pregnancy-part1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/07/29/the-unexpected-pregnancy-part1/</guid>
        
        <category>--</category>
        
        <category>Pehia</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rethinking the way we tell the tale of the computers.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I live in Kerala, a state in the far southern part of India. I was born and brought up in a small village here and had my high school education from a village school nearby. It was only by the final year of college that, I started to engage with technology communities around me, attending technology related events and grew into an active part of the tech communities here in Kerala.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became an enduring member of FOSS Kerala, a regional community of people who support and contributes to Free and Open Source software. In the first few meetups, I was literally silent because I had no clue on what was going on and on what they were discussing. All I did was that I took notes and when I was back home, I’d Google and read. I came to realize that I’ve studied all these in my high school classes. So I looked up my high school computer education syllabus and I was stunned!
All these years I had all this in my syllabus, but I had no clue on what was exactly being taught. So I was curious on how it is now, is it still the same? Are kids still being taught the same way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the time I started contributing to Pehia Foundation, a small organization helping women and underrepresented groups of society to involve more in technology. I had a talk with the headmaster of the school that I studied in and he granted me the permission to take a session on Free and Open Source Software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I continued teaching the kids, I understood that our education system is still a long way from helping the students survive in this tremendously changing world. But they were super curious. They didn’t know what open-source was, that people were contributing from all around the globe to build these awesome tools, let alone that they were using it. I talked a bit about their syllabus and how our little state is considered to be far ahead of other states in terms of computer literacy. We have a beautiful and at the same time a very powerful syllabus for our students, IT@School but still its not reaching the children in the right way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially considering how we’re discussing privacy &amp;amp; data protection and how important it is, in this day and age, and our kids were being exposed to the right tools without them knowing. Super cool isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After talking a bit about what FOSS is and how it is important, I mentioned the recent (2017) judgment about privacy as a fundamental right by the Supreme Court of India and to my surprise, they were all aware of it, but lacked clarity. It was really interactive since they knew a little bit here and there, and they were really curious to know more and didn’t hesitate to ask questions, which again surprised me. And they were really interested to know more. What else did I need? :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was really glad to share the information I knew, and honestly after hearing their questions, I felt like I really underestimated these children. I should have researched a bit more. Also, I tried to bring out their views about the Privacy Act &amp;amp; Aadhaar issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conversation ended up being really interactive, and we talked about things like how Aadhaar infringes on rights of an individual and how does Facebook decide what to show on your news feeds, how it gathers information and serves you ads based on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-63.png&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The greatness of a community is most accurately measured by the compassionate actions of its members. &lt;cite&gt;Coretta Scott King&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a moment of realization, I’ve always wanted to contribute to STEM education for children and I wanted to open the world of opportunities out there for them. Computers as a tool and how to use them have become an essential 21st century skill.
But all I see is everyone trying to make software engineers, but I wanted the children to be able to use computers as an effective tool to augment their line of work, be it health, finance or engineering. Teach them how to break down complex problems, refine their line of thought and build problem solving skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-64.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To accomplish this, there is a need to reach out to schools, create peer learning groups and provide a level ground for children from different schools, different places, different backgrounds to gather around on a single table and discussing technology by letting them build things, share knowledge, learn new things, and provide them with proper mentor-ship and domain awareness by connecting them to the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-65.png&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-66.png&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Great things are done by a series of small things brought together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-67.png&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To manage and run something like this at scale I’ll need to work on my interpersonal, management and organizational skills, I’ll need help learning how to source funds, identify need and channeling the right resources to need and requirement. For this I could use all the help that I can get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m always available on email (r k [dot] s r e e p r i y a [at] g m a i l [dot] c o m). Ping me if you could help me out in anyway, or if you are interested in the story I just told and what to know more. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The way to change the world is through individual responsibility and taking local action in your own community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/07/29/rethinking-the-way-we-tell-the-tales-of-computer-science/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/07/29/rethinking-the-way-we-tell-the-tales-of-computer-science/</guid>
        
        <category>--</category>
        
        <category>Pehia</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moved to Mumbai &amp; Joined USF</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The past few weeks has been the few of the best weeks of my life. It was like a dream come true.
Most girls I know want to live independent life, to live alone, to take care of herself, to live without the help from their family both morally and financially and to take the responsibility for their own decisions. At least this is what I wanted in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;city-of-dreams&quot;&gt;City of Dreams!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached Mumbai on May 10th. I felt happy when I saw Henna(the founder of Universe Simplified, whom I’m going to work for the next two years) waiting for me in front of her house. I wanted to hug Henna the very first moment I met her, but I didn’t. I don’t know what stopped me from doing so.
She had set up everything for me. Even though she dislikes cooking, she had set up a mini kitchen and everything I needed. A simple thank you is not enough to thank her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The place is called Dombivli and her house was a seven minutes walk from the local train station and fifteen minutes walk from my office. The market in Dombivli is near the railway station, so basically everything I need is at the doorstep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With me, my Amma &amp;amp; Brother were there. We used to go out every evening and have a walk around. To get a glimpse of this city which is unknown to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-44.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-45.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-46.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-47.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I send off my amma and brother back home, I was actually excited rather than been scared. It was really crazy to think that now I’m in Mumbai, I don’t know the local language(Marathi), I don’t anyone here(No relatives, no friends), I’m all alone in this unknown hectic city. Others will find this scary but I find it really challenging and adventurous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My day starts with an exercise which Henna suggested to me for strengthening my knees and thighs ( since I’ve ligament injury issues, sometimes it’s hard to climb stairs and walk continuously).
Then cooking. This is the part which I and Henna hate. We both don’t know how to cook and we find it boring and time-consuming. But our circumstances forcing us to cook. What to do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;then-office&quot;&gt;Then office.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-48.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s only a 10 minutes walk to the office from where we stay. I saw the Dombivli market and Henna’s chai shop. Henna is a chai addict. I really wanted to try chai there but I didn’t. I miss The chaiwallah.in very much. I wish they had a branch here with the same vibrant atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-office-universe-simplified-foundation&quot;&gt;My office: Universe Simplified Foundation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Story of why Universe Simplified was started by Henna Khan. When Henna was a kid she was really interested in astronomy but that passion was lost because our education system did not encourage questions and nurture and child’s curiosity. The focus was on rote learning with the intention of clearing exams. Many years later while working at her family business that passion came back and Universe Simplified was born with the intention of taking hands-on astronomy workshops for children so that they get a platform to explore their interest further and to ignite the spark of curiosity in children. Meera joined USF at the very beginning and both Henna and Meera made the first set of projects to take to the schools. When they started working in schools they realized that over all these years nothing has changed and that science was still being taught through textbooks. So they set up hands on, which was focused on clearing the child’s concept.
That’s a bit about USF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-first-day-at-office&quot;&gt;My first day at office&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-49.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was full of excitement. I was curious to know about my work and all. I met Sonali(Operations Intern), Sneha(HR Intern) and Anna (Innovation Fellow). Me and Anna are going to work together for the next two years at the ground level, managing innovation hubs, and training interns, etc. The fun part is Anna is a local and speaks Marathi &amp;amp; Hindi only. And me the second fellow, from Kerala and don’t know a single Marathi word and struggles in speaking Hindi. It was a question mark for everyone about how these fellows are going to communicate!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re a team of six people and twenty plus interns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing they asked me was “ What do you want to achieve in the next two year? Apart from the fellowship what do you want to learn? Think, make a list and tell us. We will help you.”
I was amazed, surprised and I don’t have any words to explain the happiness I felt. How many organization think about their team member’s personal development? USF, they’re not only concentrating on the kids’ education but the team members also. Every team member of USF has weekly tasks to complete on personal development. And we’ve beautiful weekly reflections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-reflections&quot;&gt;About reflections&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are mainly four key values UFS follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-50.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compassion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ownership&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Innovation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So on weekly reflections, each team member will share their weekly experience. And each member will try to follow these four values as possible and discuss on which value we need to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;critical-thinking&quot;&gt;Critical Thinking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In every team meeting, we’ve got a critical thinking task. Each time one team member will research on any critical thinking task and other members have to do it. USF promotes critical thinking and design thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;work-mode-on&quot;&gt;Work mode ON!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-51.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The date of joining was in April, but I couldn’t join at that time here because of some commitments I had already made. Since I had joined late,I only had half the time to finish the training. The training is basically making of small science-electronics projects. Training is inquiry-driven and hands-on. I’ve to make projects and document on my learning and the improvements that can be made in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the schools start on the second week of June. Before the schools started, we hosted a selection workshop for the volunteers. The workshop was really a fun and exciting. The volunteers do hands-on projects without the help of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we get a problem to solve, the first thing we do is to search for solutions on the internet and we apply an existing solution. Where is the innovation in this? Innovation comes only when we start thinking and sadly people have have started doing less of that. Everyone is lazy to use their brains, lazy to think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the intern selection workshop, they were asked to make a Rubber Band Plane, seems simple enough, right? But it took me roughly 9 hours to make one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While observing them making the project, it was hilarious. They came up with different ideas that I had never even thought of. The working principle will be the same for every plane, but the design they came up with were different and innovative. Some failed, some quit in the middle and some completed.
The task was not to complete it, but to get an understanding of the process, the way they executed the task and to understand the working of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the way everything works at Universe Simplified. We find the problem, then we discuss it, finds solution/solutions, plan it and then execute it.
I’m really in love with our team. We talk about everything. Not just about the education in general, but also politics, love, relationship, gender stereotyping, social structure, family, etc. I feel right at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-52.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-53.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/06/30/usf-joining/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/06/30/usf-joining/</guid>
        
        <category>--</category>
        
        <category>Work</category>
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mumbai- Work and Home </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I can’t predict the climate in Mumbai. Sometimes it’s raining and sometimes it’s hot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-35.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;work&quot;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-36.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schools have started by the end of June so did our workshops. For the last 6 years USF has been working with different schools and foundations, both in urban and rural areas of Mumbai. I’m in charge of urban areas. We have 7 innovation hubs all over Mumbai and four innovation hubs are in the urban area and two in rural area. Being an innovation fellow, it’s my responsibility to take care of these four hubs in the urban area which consists of nine batches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a diverse set of interns. From Btech students to a retired pharmaceutical sales executive. There is no discrimination on the basis of age, color, gender, etc. The only thing that matters to USF is &lt;strong&gt;CURIOSITY!&lt;/strong&gt; Your curiosity to learn new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-37.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day I was at the office working on a project and Meera, the Cofounder and Program Manager of USF gave me a task to do. I started searching on the internet. &lt;em&gt;“Sreepriya, I need you to change your learning approach,” Meera said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;learning-approach&quot;&gt;Learning Approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always end up looking up on Google whenever someone gives me a task to do. What I’ve noticed is that Google always has some solution for your problem and when I read the solution I start thinking in that perspective only. My mind gets influenced by the existing solutions and I never think about solving it in a different approach. This happens every time. Now, I started trying not to rely on the internet too much. I think about the problem, how I can solve this and then design a way to solve the problem. It may not be the best way to solve a problem but still, the problem can be solved this way too. Then I can search on the Internet and find existing solutions and think to compare the solution and arrive at a better conclusion. I’m able to see the change in my thought process. This is the same thing we do with children. They’re encouraged to think in their way and design their solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;innovation-hubs&quot;&gt;Innovation Hubs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-38.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so happy with my job. It’s not a 9 to 5 job. I only have to work for three days a week. Saturday, Sunday, Monday and one-off day in a week. These three days I’ll be traveling around Mumbai, to Juhu, Lokhandwala, Andheri, and Lower Parel. These are the places where we have our innovation hubs. Rest of the days I will be at our office in Dombivli, making small mechanical projects and learning electronics and programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;USF has a level-based curriculum, Titanium is the lowest level, then Iron, Copper, and Zinc respectively, for now. Titanium and Iron levels include small mechanical and electronics projects. Children are exposed to making projects using solar panels, motors, LEDs, etc. From balloon-powered car, to a water rocket, children are doing amazing DIY projects. We, facilitators, give hints when they’re stuck. Children are encourged to do project on their own. We never say what’s right and what’s wrong. They have the complete freedom to fail and we do celebrate failures at USF. Children are so curious to make things and we are amazed by the ideas they come up with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-39.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-innovation-hub-managers-interns&quot;&gt;The Innovation Hub Managers/ Interns.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bunch of amazing people, with a huge passion for learning, making and sharing their knowledge. They are working as part-time interns. I’ve to observe them and give feedback/suggestion on their facilitation style. Some are extraordinary in facilitating children. They were good at managing children too. Sometimes it’s really difficult to manage children. Children are very chaotic. I do remember my first session at one of our innovation hub and children were running around all the time. We couldn’t even talk to them properly because they were not even listening to us. I was able to figure out what to do. I was not prepared enough because I was not expecting this. Then I simply sit in the corner of the classroom and let the children do whatever they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-40.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are trying to figure out how to deal with these children and it’s different for different hubs. At some innovation hubs, we start with five minutes of fun activities to gain their attention and for some other hubs, we start with a critical thinking activity which increases the team collaboration between the children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-41.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One full-day workshop at ATE Enterprise office, Andheri. It was really fun, making projects and testing it. Everyone has their childish behavior in them. I got to see that while testing the water rocket project, and trying out the water balloon challenge. The duration of this internship is for six months. We are a family right now. Young minds from all over Mumbai coming together to learn new things a Intern Training Day and share their leanings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, that’s a bit about my work and workspace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;life-in-mumbai&quot;&gt;Life in Mumbai&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Henna for helping me in finding a new place. I’ve always dreamed of about living on my own. It’s really exciting. Even though I hate cooking, it gives me some sort of pleasure when I cook at night. I’m more relaxed after cooking and I feel a kind of freshness inside. I become more productive at night. The only problem I’m dealing right now is my sleeping irregularity and I’m unsure about what to do with it. Apart from that, I’m so happy here. I’m investing more time for myself and I’m doing something I love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always wanted to learn psychology. Two books which I’m reading right now is “ The Power of Habit” by Charles Duhigg and “What did you ask at school today?” by Kamala V Mukunda. Both books are connected. One is dealing with how the brain works and why we are doing what we do. The other book is a handbook for child psychology. It goes into depth on how the young brains works. Suggestion are welcome for any interesting books related to this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-42.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/15/usf-work-and-life-mumbai/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/01/15/usf-work-and-life-mumbai/</guid>
        
        <category>--</category>
        
        <category>Work</category>
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Zee Camp 2019 </title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;A 14 day camp organized for transgender community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those forteen days were unforgettable. It was a totally new experience for me. That was the first time, we closely dealt with the transgender community. We (Pehia Foundation) tried our best to make them feel comfortable, to create welcoming environment for them. 13 days, 3 different courses, around 10–15 transgender persons from all over Kerala.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog, I would like to share my personal experiences working with them and the curiosity I had while being with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The venue was Santhigiri Ashram in Aluva. &lt;strong&gt;Zee Camp 2019&lt;/strong&gt; was a collaborative effort of the &lt;strong&gt;Pehia Foundation&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;Marthoma Navodaya Society&lt;/strong&gt;. The event was from Jan 5th, 2019 to Jan 13th, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program agenda was like &lt;strong&gt;Advanced Microsoft&lt;/strong&gt; Office training in the first three days, then &lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Programming using Python&lt;/strong&gt; for the next three days and in the last three days an &lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Web Development&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Enfa (cofounder of Pehia Foundation) had a class and part-time internship, she visited the program after her work. Me and Diya Liza Varghese (Volunteer) was there at the venue full time. Thank you so much to the Marthoma Navodaya Society for supporting us on this journey. They arranged food and accommodation for us and as well as for participants and speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-0&quot;&gt;Day 0&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;jan-4th-2019&quot;&gt;Jan 4th, 2019&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was there at Santhigiri Ashram by evening 5 pm. We were expecting our fellow participants to be there by 6 pm. They came late because some strike was announced for the next two days all over Kerala. We(Me and Enfa) ‘were so happy. Because it was our dream to do something useful for the transgender community. In the initial stages of the Pehia Foundation, there were so many people who discouraged us from not to involve in transgender communities. Actually, they were not saying it, it felt like a warning to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were scared too. I agree. We were afraid of the unknown. But we didn’t give up. We find different ways to reach these communities and thanks to Pirate Praveen and Sooraj Kenoth for connecting with Vijaya Raja Malika and Jijo Kuriakose from Queerala. We used to go for monthly meetups of Queerala to know the community and its members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally the effort we put in started showing results. Our participants are here. We had dinner together. We took the initiative to build small conversations with them and we made sure that they’re comfortable. From the first day itself, they started their life experiences with us. They shared their feelings when their family and society rejected them. Some of them have not yet revealed their identity in their family. We sat with them and listen to them. We came to the problems they faced that we’d never imagined were there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;advanced-microsoft-office-training&quot;&gt;Advanced Microsoft Office Training&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first course, we only had four participants, and &lt;strong&gt;Mr. Saji Kumar&lt;/strong&gt; was their tutor. Saji sir has 6-year experience in training MS office. When I searched for a trainer, first concerned was whether they will be comfortable in mentoring the transgender community. I was really scared by the societal stereotyping which we were trying to undo through Pehla Foundation. When I spoke to Saji sir, he said that he had never trained transgender people and he doesn’t know how it will go. This was his only concern. I felt like we came to the right person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He really was. Three day MS Office training turned out to be the best of three sessions we have planned. Our participants was so happy and comfortable with their mentor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Saji sir treated us like his small sister. “- feedback from one of our Zee camp fellow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these three days, they covered MS Word, MS power point and MS Excel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too many people asked us &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Why MS Office training?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My answer to the question is, we organized Zee Camp for sharing some knowledge with the transgender community and we realized what they need is skills to get employment. We were not trying to make them programmers. This MS training was to upskill the community members so that they found more employable in-office tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction-to-programming-using-python&quot;&gt;Introduction to Programming using Python&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-22.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;
The second session was the introduction to programming using python and &lt;strong&gt;Anusree S&lt;/strong&gt;, team members of Pehia Foundation take lead for the session. An intro to git and GitHub were also included in the curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Engaging with them was a different experience in my life,” Anusree S said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team was as curious as I was. This was our experiment event with the transgender community. Before the event, we were just quality advocated I would say. We tried to spread gender awareness through our programs. We held healthy discussions on gender awareness in every program we organize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do remember, I and Enfa went for a talk together and after our session, one girl from the audience met us in person after the session and said that she is a bisexual. That time we were not connected with the LGBTQI community like &lt;strong&gt;Queerala&lt;/strong&gt;. If we were connected at least it would have helped her to get mental/emotional support from the Queerala community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the second day, we had &lt;strong&gt;Rahul Ramesh, CTO, Entri App&lt;/strong&gt; for mentoring our Zee camp fellows. Some of them were really interested in learning programming and others find it very difficult to understand the logic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the third day, we were discussing the Transgender bill Amendment. You can find my views on Transgender Bill here soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction-to-website-development&quot;&gt;Introduction to Website Development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-23.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr. Geon George&lt;/strong&gt; was the trainer. He was an engineering student and a good friend of Diya, our Ze camp volunteer. Geon is a great person, a simple thank you is not enough to thank him for supporting us and for being there in Pehia’s dream project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our number of participants increased. For web development, we had ten participants. Both transmen and transwomen persons. I met Hrithik there. He is a very charm person and soon we become friends. He is working as News Reader at Jeevan TV now. He and Tripthi Shetty become the second transgender couple in Kerala.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geon’s session was very interactive. He started it with the history of internet and web. I had the privilege to assist him with this track. While he explained how to use Visual Studio Code and HTML on the first day, I give them challenges to solve using what they have learned in the previous track. On the third day, Geon introduced varies web frameworks and resources to learn it. Because we know that with one or two days’ session none can master a skill. They need to practice what they’ve learned. So he shared some valuable resources with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giri Chandanakadan, a transman and a Pehia Zee camp fellow 2019 have been placed in Profisglobal as a web/graphics designer. I hope Pehia will be able to host more such camps for transgender communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zee camp 2019 was one of the dream projects of Pehla Foundation which we really work hard for it to happen. Our sincere thanks to Preeti, program coordinator from &lt;strong&gt;Marthoma Navodaya Society&lt;/strong&gt; for making this event possible and Rev Binu for providing the venue, food, and accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope we can organize more impactful programs in future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/15/zee-camp-2019/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/01/15/zee-camp-2019/</guid>
        
        <category>--</category>
        
        <category>Pehia</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Intern's Life at BHGE</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-68.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;last-day-selfie&quot;&gt;Last day selfie.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While everyone was celebrating this Christmas Eve, I was quite sad. Because December 24th, 2018 was my last working day at BHGE. I came here at BHGE with no clue about what I want to go further in my career. And now I’m leaving here this Christmas Eve with a thought about which field I can excel in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-69.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined BHGE on last 25th June. I was lucky enough to get an internship at such an MNC very soon after my graduation. My role was to support the new learning portal they’re building for their new hires and also assisting the Skill Pool Manager of BHGE, Kochi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BHGE is spread across two floors of SmartCity, Kochi. I was on the 3rd floor working with the Digital Technology team. Since I was working closely with the Skill Pool Manager, I got to know deep about BHGE, its organizational hierarchy, and tools available in BHGE for employees’ interpersonal skill development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-70.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;networks-in-bhge&quot;&gt;Networks in BHGE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I understood, BHGE invests a lot in community activities. A worldwide network of Women in Energy, Women in Technology, and Women in Rig are global communities within BHGE. The activities of these communities within BHGE and the recognition they give to women was amazing. BHGE even has a global interns community in Facebook and I got the opportunity to know a few interns working in Digital Technology in BHGE, Houston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I mainly liked about BHGE is the hospitality they give to their employees. They have supported me in activities of Pehia Foundation and most importantly they stood by my side when wrong allegations came against me during the flood in Kerala.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;friends-and-colleagues&quot;&gt;Friends and colleagues&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-71.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;interns&quot;&gt;Interns!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we are a family. Four interns, two from north India and two from Kerala. Since I had no clue about the petroleum industry, its history and how much petroleum influences our daily life etc, it was fun and informative working with them. Thanks, Prachi Uppu (my co-intern) for teaching me from the basics. I was her testing material for every domain material she creates for the new learning portal. Her theory was if I could understand the materials they created, then anyone could. And it worked. Now I’m confident enough to write a petroleum examination. She taught me from the evolution of earth to the latest tools being developed in BHGE for drilling. Off the record, yeah! I’ve got a mini petroleum degree now. 😂😂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;haseena-manjandavida&quot;&gt;Haseena Manjandavida!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-72.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was ex-military and a great personality. It was my pleasure to meet and work with her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-73.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event “Untitled” conducted by MEC, Thrikkakara, Haseena was a speaker there. And her travel story is really a huge inspiration for every girl who loves to travel — especially for the ones who love long bike rides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-74.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sports-meet&quot;&gt;Sports Meet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-75.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-76.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a huge fan of football. I stopped playing football three years ago because I suffered an injury while playing football and my family was too scared to let me play again. And I quit.
On BHGE sports day, I had the opportunity to play football again and I really enjoyed the moment. I never thought I would be ever able to play again but I got a chance here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-77.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-78.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the Annual family gathering!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-79.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-80.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-81.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Annual day preparation made me think of my school/college art days. And it was the first time I did a fashion show. Now everyone is calling me “Helen/Monica”. That was really fun. My last days in BHGE was excellent. I became close to everyone in BHGE. Really, I’m gonna miss these people. I enjoyed every moment with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The words “Thank you” is not enough to show my gratitude towards Miss Keerthana Krishnan. The one who referred me for this opportunity at BHGE. After my graduation, I had no idea about what I was going to do. It was then I got a message from Geeky Purple Unicorn that there is an opening of an internship at BHGE. I suddenly said yes to her and then I got a call from Zarina, who was working as a Skill Pool Manager, at BHGE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;zarina-aziz&quot;&gt;Zarina Aziz&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-82.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-83.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first manager and a very supportive woman. A role model I would say. Her personal and professional life has inspired me very much. I love the way she works and the effort she put in to reach higher levels in her career. She is currently working at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.neudesic.com/&quot;&gt;Neudesic Business Technology Solution&lt;/a&gt; as a Sr. Manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was never bossy. she helped me to learn and understand new things quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was a friend. One day she took me to her new flat and met her family. I could always see that smile of accomplishment on her face. I’ve so much love and gratitude towards her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining BHGE was a Herculean task. Got a lot of documents to sign and a full health check-up and finally, I joined BHGE on June 25th, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six months!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was really a great opportunity I got to learn, understand and explore.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/12/30/six-months-internship-at-bhge/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/12/30/six-months-internship-at-bhge/</guid>
        
        <category>--</category>
        
        <category>Work</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>K4Kode - A Pehia Foundation initiative</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K4Kode&lt;/strong&gt; is an initiative under &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;PEHIA FOUNDATION&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; focusing to provide access to Information Technology for children with a goal to improve the participation of females and underprivileged minorities in tech industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-computers&quot;&gt;Why Computers?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are living in an age of information technology where every aspect of our life has its influenced by it, starting from internet of things to automation by Artificial Intelligence. Everyday start with an alarm set in our mobile phones and end by checking the notifications of your favourite social media apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information technology is indeed our present and future, but how to crack into that field?
To use a computer, you dont need to learn anything specific. Academic projects, assignments, video games,make your child close enough with the computers. But the main part is understanding how a computer works,which makes the difference. Programming is the linguistic management of computers and learning the language enlighten your child to bright future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Children must be taught how to think, not what to think.”
&lt;cite&gt;Margaret Mead &lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-girls&quot;&gt;Why Girls?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;According to a study by &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.intel.com/news-releases/new-intel-report-finds-making-can-engage-girls-in-computer-science-and-engineering-potentially-reducing-tech-gender-gap/&quot;&gt;Intel in America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 out of 3 female makers say lack of mentorship is a challenge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 out of 6 have been excluded from making due to gender discrimination.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 out of 6 face cultural biases about the appropriateness of women in making.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 out of 14 doesn’t feel safe going to the places where maker activities are held.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of your female friends are already aware of these issues, might have direct experience also, but how to solve these?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Improve the women participation in IT industry”&lt;/em&gt;, it is both the solution and the goal. Improving the participation of women in IT industry will solve four out of four problems above and give confidence to next generation of girls for joining this industry, which is ultimately the goal of this program, to reduce the gender gap. Here we intend to solve these issues by giving girl child a safe atmosphere, tools, good mentorship from experienced professionals and opportunities to excel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-do-we-do&quot;&gt;what do we do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have to,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gather&lt;/strong&gt; resources and funds from established companies who are interested in contributing to this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;create&lt;/strong&gt; a safe atmosphere for your children to follow their passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;provide&lt;/strong&gt; mentorship by experts in respective fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;find&lt;/strong&gt; opportunities for your children, so that they can obtain first hand experience in the industry with which they can perform well and be more productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;help&lt;/strong&gt; your child to find a better future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-should-you-do&quot;&gt;what should you do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know that female participation in the technology industry remains a challenging issue. Despite increasing numbers over the past few years, women are still vastly underrepresented in IT companies, and in particular, executive and entrepreneurial roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rome can’t be built in a day, but these initiatives can be. So, let’s all hold hands together for a better future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/06/12/k4kode-pehia-foundation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/06/12/k4kode-pehia-foundation/</guid>
        
        <category>--</category>
        
        <category>Pehia</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pehia and Me!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you know any girl who loves to play football? If you don’t, now you know one. ☺&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-54.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From childhood, I was a jack of all trades. In my school days, I always tried to excel in extracurricular activities and as well as in academics. I don’t know when I started manifesting an interest in football. Maybe because of my first crush was a football player at that time. :P I started playing football at the age of 10. I was a very stubborn and proactive child at that time. My family has always supported me in everything I do. They said a clear NO when I talked about me practicing football.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-55.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the first time they stopped me from doing something that I love. But I never listened to them as I was so stubborn and determined to get whatever I want. I started playing football. Negative comments started popping up one by one. Even from the family itself. The saddest part was, they know I play well and I love playing football, but they don’t want me to go for practice just because I’m a girl. I fell down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that never stopped me from playing football. When I joined Sacred Heart HSS, Thevara for my higher secondary education, the first thing I searched for was about the women’s football team but sadly there was only women’s cricket team. I couldn’t find any other girls playing football and I put a halt for my football dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day when I came back home after my class. My mom said that she met her old friend and he was asking about me and how my football practicing going on. I felt really sad. I went into a state of depression. Because of knowing that I’m simply giving up my dreams without trying. I started thinking about how to restart playing football, where I can do practice, where I will be able to find a coach. When I tried, I found the answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One question remained unanswered. How I will convince my parents?
I fast for a few days. I didn’t eat anything, drunk anything for days. I still don’t know why I choose to fast even though it is not a solution to my problem. But it worked. (Note: Doesn’t work always)
Finally, my family said that do whatever you want. Still, that was not a YES but it was more than enough for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-56.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, back on the field. I was happy and happier when I got selected as a central midfielder for the Alappuzha district team. After hours and hours of trying to convince my family, I went to Wayanad to play the very first Ramco Kerala Women’s League.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-57.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tragedy struck when I got injured during the match and had to be bed-ridden for a few months. This incident forced me to give in to my family’s decision and I had to say goodbye to my football dreams. For me, that was a sad phase in my life, but eventually, that incident had a huge part in making me whom I’m today.
I vowed then that I will fight to ensure that girls have the freedom to make their own decisions in life. That’s how I become the co-founder of Pehia Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/placeholder-58.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My parents considered girls playing football as odd because there weren’t any examples for me to show them. The same issue happened with the conferences and workshops. Then I met Enfa, who shared a similar interest to attend events, conferences, hackathons etc, and then we both decided to start Pehia Community. A community for like-minded girls to support each other,to learn and to grow, together for building a better future for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/02/the-unexpected-pregnancy-part2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/10/02/the-unexpected-pregnancy-part2/</guid>
        
        <category>--</category>
        
        <category>Pehia</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
